# Aliaksei **Bliznichenka**

Minsk, Belarus

□ +375 (33) 639-26-03 | ■ a1exandddrovich@gmail.com | In aliaksei bliznichenka | • a1exanddrovich

## Summary

A passionate AWS certified software engineer with 2+ years of demonstrated industry experience, who thinks "out of the box" to provide software solutions. Looking for a professional team to implement knowledge and gain experience, to grow and contribute. Previous accomplishments include increased contribution to Minsk Java Community as educational courses author, integration application with Amazon Web Services, obtaining AWS Developer certification.

## Skills

**Back-end** Java 8/11, Jakarta EE, Spring (Core, Boot, MVC, Data, Security, WebFlux), JPA (Hibernate), Maven, MVEL, JUnit, Liquibase, SQL, JUnit, Mockito, REST API, OOP, Software Design Patterns, TDD, Micro Service Architecture;

**DevOps** Git, Docker, Jenkins; **Front-end** Thymleaf, JSP, JSF;

**Tools** Postman, Kafka, RabbitMQ, Jira, Confluence, Amazon Web Services, Agile, Scrum;

**Languages** English, Belarusian, Russian.

# **Experience**

## **EPAM Systems, Inc | London Stock Exchange Group project**

Minsk, Belarus

Software Engineer May 2022 - present

- · Identified memory leak parts of a framework and refactored them which reduced memory consumption by 20%;
- Were responsible for a sub team developing separate AWS utilities for processing specific data and troubleshooting which reduced the time spent by analysts and testers by 30%;
- Supervised the framework migration from Java 8 to Java 11;
- · Contributed to the team survival during crisis and ramped up involvement of newcomers in the platform development which decreased onboarding time by 50%;
- Technologies: Java 11, AWS, Docker, REST, GitLab, Jenkins, MVEL, Sonar.

### **EPAM Systems, Inc | Refinitiv project**

Minsk. Belarus

Junior Software Engineer

Sep. 2021 - May 2022

- Developed business logic for 9 lambda functions according to the activity diagrams, provided by BA's;
- Integrated application with Amazon Web Services Lambda, SQS, S3, DynamoDB, CloudFormation, CloudWatch & others;
- Explored internal Refinitiv's bitemporal storage which led to increased efficiency usage of its API by 20%;
- Increased test coverage by 40%, which significantly reduced amount of regression bugs;
- Technologies: Java 8, AWS, Docker, REST, GitLab, Jenkins, MVEL

#### Courses

#### **EPAM Systems, Inc** Minsk, Belarus

· Developed a RESTful API server from scratch based on the Spring Framework;

Internship July 2021 - Aug. 2021

- Set up ORM with Java Persistence API (Hibernate used as its implementation);
- Configured i10n and i18n with 2 languages built-in;
- · Implemented authentication based on JWT;
- · Joined a team based on the results of the conducted interviews;
- Technologies: Java 11, Spring Framework (Core, MVC, Boot, Security, Data), JPA, Hibernate, JUnit5, Postman, Postgres;

#### **EPAM Systems, Inc** Minsk, Belarus

• Built a Jakarta EE web-application from scratch;

Jan. 2021 - July 2021

- Integrated the application with Tomcat and MySQL;
- Implemented front end making use of JSP, JavaScript, HTML, CSS;
- Fully covered code with unit and integration tests;
- · Received an offer from the company based on the studying results and conducted interviews;
- Technologies: Java 8, Jakarta EE, JDBC, Servlets, Tomcat, JSP, JSTL, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, MySQL;

## **Education**

Student

#### **BSUIR (Belarusian State University of Informatics and Radioelectronics)**

Minsk, Belarus

Bachelor's Degree in Information Technologies Engineering

• Diploma theme "Automated Multidimensional Database Processing System"